Santiago Vasco Tabares

Career Summary

Software engineer with +5 years of experience working with international clients as a backend developer, currently working with Java building RESTful Web services. Experience in Java, Gosu (Guidewire), databases like DynamoDB, Firestore, MongoDB, PostgreSQL and MySQL. In personal projects I worked with HTML, CSS and Javascript in frameworks like Angular and Ionic for hybrid mobile apps. Also, skills working with CI/CD, Agile methodologies and multicultural teams.

Contact

svascot@gmail.com

+57 304 4864344

Summary of Qualifications

Java

• AWS (EC2, DynamoDb, S3, Route 53)

• JUnit

Mockito

Git

Gosu

Dynamo

PSQL

Jenkins

Sonar

Codenarc

Scrum

Career History

FastSpring - FastSpring / Team Int Jun 2021 - current.

Full service e-commerce platform for companies that sell software and other online digital products. Implementation of new features and continuously improving the product using Java Corretto 11, AWS, Postgresql, DynamoDB, CI/CD with Jenkins. Full remote and agile environment.

Disney Parks - Globant Dic 2019 - Jun 2021

Development of new services which handle the information, tasks, benefits and tools that help employees to perform their daily work. The project has a Web platform and a Mobile app that uses BackEnd in Java running over GCP instances.

Viliv - Globant Jun 2019 - Dic 2019

A backend made with Microservices to handle the business logic for a company that helps StartUps in their maturation process, Java with Spring Boot, AWS instances and MongoDB.

• NFL OTT apps - Globant Dic 2018 - Jun 2019

Development of features in OTT application for major US Sports league, using C++ with You.I framework. Besides, an API implementation in Java with Spring Boot that consumes several REST resources of different platforms was done. Then the data was processed and exposed through a new endpoint.

New Core Sura - Ceiba Software Jan 2016 - Dic 2018

Implementation Policy Center Module with Gosu Guidewire, Integration of continuous integration and continuous delivery with jenkins, Reduction of Sonar incidents and increase the code coverage based on Codenar reports.

Gestión de Riesgos y Asistencia Sura - Ceiba Software Jan 2015 - Jan 2016
Web platform built in AngularJS, Backend In Java and a SQL Database to manage Salud Sura clients, users and employee information.

Education

• Bachelor degree:

Universidad EAFIT (2010-2015) Activities and Societies: Java, C++, Angular, Photoshop, 3D Printers Medellín - Colombia

• Foundational Computer Science Courses – An Industry Perspective

Took a course called "Foundational Computer Science Courses - An Industry Perspective" in which I received training in Java technologies like JSP, JSF and JPA. As well as web technologies such as HTML, CSS and Javascript.

Infosys, Mysore - India (2013)

High School:

I.E. Concejo de Medellín School (2009) - Technician Software Design and Programming. Medellín - Colombia

Portfolio

• http://santiagovasco.com

Accomplishments

- Winner Google start-up weekend 2014, with an App to rent public service vehicles.
- Winner Proyecto Integrador Universidad EAFIT System to manage turns in Banks and Hospitals using a control panel to send a push notification to the next user.